Dhruv Patel

Full-Stack Developer

■ Node.js | express.js | React.js | MongoDB | MySQL 🕜 Portfolio 🛅 LinkedIn

Profile

Responsible **Full-Stack Developer**, passionate about delivering outstanding quality and service, offering 3+ years of experience in the industry with a history of recognition for performance.

Skills

Libraries & Frameworks: Node.js, express.js, React.js, Typescript

Database Knowledge: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

API Development & Integration: REST API

Payment Gateway Integration: Stripe, Paypal, In-App-Purchase

Tools & Technology: VS Code, GitHub, GitLab, Slack, MySQL Workbench

Version Control: Github, Gitlab

Social Integration: Facebook, Google, Apple

Cloud & Hosting: AWS EC2, Domain Hosting & Management, SSL

Professional Experience

Iroid Solutions

02/2022 - present | Surat, India

- Work with multiple technologies such as Node.js, Express.js, React.js and Typescript.also use multiple databases like MongoDB, MYSQL and PostgreSQL.
- Worked on the multiple project like Finance Management, Prediction Stocks Platform, Social Media, Educational Projects, Service Marketplace, Facility Management etc.
- Developed functional databases, applications, and servers to support websites on the back-end. Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas requiring improvement.
- Implementing security best practices in Node.js applications, including data validation, input sanitization, authentication and authorization.
- Integrated Socket.io for real-time communication in web applications to enhance user experience and functionality.
- Configured and deployed existing and future REST APIs, integrating with third-party APIs.Performed troubleshooting of technical issues within the production environment.
- Used AWS EC2 service, setting up and managing EC2 instances, deploying projects, configuring SSL certificates, and hosting applications.
- Planned, designed, and deployed web applications with REST APIs using Node.js, ensuring code is clean and efficient. Also, focused on data modeling, querying, and security.
- Explore new technologies and learn about them. Mentored junior members and delivered training to boost team skills set.

Crystal Infotech

02/2021 - 01/2022 | Surat, India

- Worked as MERN stack developer to design and develop Websites & APIs.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with React.js, Node.js, and Express.js.
- Provided front-end website development using React.js.
- Created REST APIs for mobile applications.
- Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, updating old versions to be more user-friendly

Education

M.Sc Cs, Shree Ramkrishna Institute of Computer Education and Applied Science

2020 – 2022 | Surat, India

Declaration

I am Dhruv Patel, hereby declare that the information contained here is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.